addition to scalability is privacy.
除了可扩展性之外，还有隐私性。
So we are actually enabling a new kind
所以我们实际上正在启用一种新的
of a privacy preserving applications starting
隐私保护应用程序启动
with ZK powered perpetual swap exchanges.
与 ZK 驱动的永续交换交易所。
For example, we are working with Aster that
例如，我们正在与 Aster 合作
allows you to essentially submit orders that
本质上允许您提交订单
is privacy protected.
隐私受到保护。
So you don't actually, you want to be actually
所以你实际上并不想成为
able to see others orders or others positions
能够看到其他订单或其他仓位
in the perpetual swap exchange that is fully decentralized
在完全去中心化的永续合约交易所中
while at the same time ensure that the security is actually
同时确保安全性确实
maintained at a blockchain level.
维持在区块链级别。
So in fact, more recently we have
所以事实上，最近我们有
been working with an ecosystem like BNB Chain, which is also
一直在与 BNB Chain 等生态系统合作，该生态系统也是
Ethereum VM based to enable a general framework
基于以太坊虚拟机以实现通用框架
for privacy preserving applications to bring off
用于隐私保护应用程序的实现
chain information to the on chain work.
将信息链到链上工作。
That is, you are able to essentially prove
也就是说，你基本上能够证明
that you are, for example, a certain kind
例如，你是某一种
of a centralized exchange user to the on chain application
中心化交易所用户到链上应用程序
without actually revealing your exact identity.
而不实际透露您的确切身份。
So as I mentioned, we have been working a lot
正如我提到的，我们做了很多工作
with stable token and real world assets.
拥有稳定的代币和现实世界的资产。
So the problem about stable token and the real world
那么关于稳定代币和现实世界的问题
assets today is that once you issue these assets,
今天的资产就是一旦你发行了这些资产，
the biggest problem is how do you get distribution?
最大的问题是如何获得分配？
How do you get data adopted?
如何让数据被采用？
Well, you actually need to integrate this
嗯，你实际上需要整合这个
with the entire on chain DeFi ecosystem
与整个链上 DeFi 生态系统
and the financial ecosystem.
和金融生态系统。
So to do that, you actually need to have a distribution
所以要做到这一点，你实际上需要有一个发行版
program that tracks user's interaction with your protocol
跟踪用户与您的协议的交互的程序
across all these different applications and interactions.
跨越所有这些不同的应用程序和交互。
How do you build a trust free and transparent architecture
如何构建一个免信任且透明的架构
for this so that a user can participate
为此，以便用户可以参与
in this with high confidence in the security
对此，我们对安全性充满信心
is something of an unsolved challenge
是一个未解决的挑战
until we arrive in the market.
直到我们到达市场。
So we built something called continuous protocol
所以我们建立了一个叫做连续协议的东西
incentivization that allows you to essentially build
激励措施可以让你从根本上建立
this transparent real world asset and stable token growth
这种透明的现实世界资产和稳定的代币增长
program.
程序。
And we have helped with many different stable token
我们已经帮助了许多不同的稳定代币
protocols to distribute hundreds of millions
分发数亿的协议
of incentives and tokens per year to their end users.
每年向最终用户提供的激励和代币。
And we have been also helping many of the new chains
我们也一直在帮助许多新的连锁店
growth here that allows you to essentially grow
在这里成长可以让你本质上成长
the new chain with the same kind of concept
同概念的新连锁店
of building a transparent and trust
建立透明和信任
free scalable and incentive distribution programs.
免费的可扩展和激励分配计划。
So my conclusion here is that verifiable computing
所以我的结论是可验证计算
is a really kind of a cutting edge and noble concept
确实是一种前沿而崇高的概念
in computing that allows you to offload
在允许您卸载的计算中
some very complex computation away from blockchain
一些远离区块链的非常复杂的计算
to this off chain world so that you can actually
到这个链外世界，这样你实际上就可以
tap into infinite amount of computing power
发挥无限的计算能力
that were not available before.
以前是不可用的。
And we believe that in 10 years, 99%
我们相信 10 年内，99%
of computation for a blockchain application
区块链应用程序的计算
is going to happen off chain.
将会发生在链下。
And it's going to be verifiable with ZK proof and hopefully
并且可以通过 ZK 证明进行验证，希望如此
by Brevis.
由布雷维斯.
So finally, I want to touch on how
最后，我想谈谈如何
we build a decentralized network for this kind of a computation
我们为这种计算构建了一个去中心化网络
to happen, right?
发生，对吗？
So this is happening off chain.
所以这是在链外发生的。
So how do you make sure that this is actually
那么你如何确保这实际上是
kind of stable and secure from kind of a user's perspective
从用户的角度来看，稳定且安全
with high liveness is something of a unique challenge.
具有高活性是一个独特的挑战。
So in this entire computing stack,
所以在整个计算堆栈中，
we also have something called a Brevis Prover Network.
我们还有一个叫做 Brevis Prover Network 的东西。
So any kind of a proving workload
所以任何类型的证明工作量
that you want to kind of do is actually
你想做的实际上是
distributed to this decentralized approving
分发给这个分散审批
network that allows you to run this truthful online double
网络，让您可以运行这个真实的在线双打
auction system and to connect with an infinite amount
拍卖系统并连接无限量
of computing power off chain so they can actually
链下计算能力，这样他们实际上就可以
generate these ZK proof for you securely
安全地为您生成这些 ZK 证明
and with extremely high availability.
并具有极高的可用性。
And we have this prover network live today.
今天我们已经上线了这个证明网络。
So that's all.
就这样。
Hopefully, I have given you guys a quick introduction
希望我已经给你们做了一个快速的介绍
of how verifiable computing work today
当今可验证计算的工作原理
and some of the amazing and exciting applications
以及一些令人惊奇和令人兴奋的应用程序
that you can build with.
你可以用它来构建。
If you have any questions, I will be around after this session.
如果您有任何疑问，我会在本次会议结束后在场。
Come find me and talk to me.
来找我，跟我说话。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Thank you, Michael.
谢谢你，迈克尔。
Our next speaker is Tina Zheng, co-founder and steward
我们的下一位演讲者是联合创始人兼管家蒂娜·郑
at Flashbot, diving into application controlled
在 Flashbot，深入研究应用程序控制
execution, Ethereum competitiveness from DeFi
执行力、以太坊竞争力来自 DeFi
to FinTech to agent applications.
到金融科技到代理应用程序。
Please welcome Tina.
请欢迎蒂娜。
Tess, Tess.
苔丝，苔丝。
All right.
好的。
So it's really great to go right after Dong Mo's presentation
所以在董默的演讲结束后就去真是太棒了
about verifiable off chain infrastructure
关于可验证的链下基础设施
because this is basically how we can
因为这基本上就是我们可以做到的
move the computation off chain while keeping our on chain
将计算移出链，同时保持链上
guarantees, which is really important for enabling agency,
担保，这对于授权机构来说非常重要，
human agency in our application design.
我们的应用程序设计中的人类代理。
So in this talk, I want to try to tie all of the bits
所以在这次演讲中，我想尝试将所有内容联系起来
and pieces that you've heard today
以及您今天听到的作品
in a more theoretical and more design framework focused talk.
在更具理论性和更多设计框架的演讲中。
So the key question I want to zoom into in this talk
所以我想在这次演讲中重点讨论的关键问题
is, what are we actually building with all of this?
是，我们实际上用这一切来构建什么？
And I want to pause and let's think about for a moment,
我想暂停一下，让我们想一下，
what is agency?
什么是代理？
Agency is the ability to act on your own behalf
代理是代表您自己行事的能力
with knowledge of what you're doing
知道你在做什么
and the ability to verify the outcome.
以及验证结果的能力。
At least that's my definition.
至少这是我的定义。
And when we're entering the agentic era,
当我们进入代理时代时，
when we speak about agentic applications,
当我们谈论代理应用程序时，
the system that matters will be the one that holistically
重要的系统将是一个从整体上
can preserve human agency over execution.
可以在执行过程中保留人类的能动性。
And I'll unpack this in my talk.
我将在演讲中解开这一点。
So every application has this similar shape
所以每个应用程序都有类似的形状
ever since the word application has been defined.
自从应用这个词被定义以来。
Input, logic, outcome.
输入、逻辑、结果。
It applies to payment, search, trading, even an LLM
它适用于支付、搜索、交易，甚至是法学硕士
can be seen by some.
有些人可以看到。
The interface level feels like an application.
界面层感觉就像一个应用程序。
At least you download it in your app stores, right?
至少你在应用商店下载了它，对吧？
But what changed today is who controls
但今天改变的是谁控制
how the outcome that you want, that the human intent
你想要的结果如何，人类的意图
is executed, and what outcome at the end of the day
被执行了，最终的结果是什么
is produced for me and for each of you.
是为我和你们每个人制作的。
So I want to quickly run through how applications has evolved.
所以我想快速了解一下应用程序是如何演变的。
And so over time, ever since, is it better?
随着时间的推移，从那时起，情况变得更好了吗？
I don't know how it sounds like for you guys.
我不知道你们听起来怎么样。
OK.
好的。
Hi, Patrick.
嗨，帕特里克。
So yeah, so basically over time, I
所以是的，基本上随着时间的推移，我
feel like our human interaction with the concept of computers
感觉就像我们人类与计算机概念的交互
has evolved.
已经进化了。
And the concept of applications has
应用程序的概念已经
evolved from desktop, web, mobile, all the way to social.
从桌面、网络、移动，一直发展到社交。
And you can see that as I laid out on the screen
你可以看到我在屏幕上展示的内容
how control has moved away from each of us,
控制权如何远离我们每个人，
how more and more layers of abstraction and intermediary
如何越来越多的抽象层和中介层
has been added to make things more convenient,
添加了使事情变得更方便，
to make things happen for us.
让事情发生在我们身上。
But we're losing, and we have been losing control.
但我们正在失败，我们一直在失去控制。
And here, specifically, I think that what
在这里，具体来说，我认为
I wanted to kind of zoom in on is circle,
我想放大一下圆圈，
all the way through the right.
一直通过右边。
I think that we're at this more or less pivotal moment
我认为我们正处于这个或多或少的关键时刻
in history where on-chain applications gives agency back
历史上，链上应用程序重新赋予了代理权
to the users.
给用户。
And this is hardened through a set of infrastructure shifts
通过一系列基础设施的转变，这一点得到了强化
in how our intents get executed.
我们的意图如何得到执行。
A key question I wanted to kind of focus on today
我今天想关注的一个关键问题
is, can an application be built without handing the control
是，可以在不交出控制权的情况下构建应用程序吗？
to any single layers of the machine that
到机器的任何单层
make decisions for us that takes away control
为我们做出剥夺控制权的决定
at the end of the day?
归根结底？
So first, since we're on Ethereum Application Day
首先，因为我们正值以太坊申请日
at Web3 Festival, a concept we've been very familiar,
在 Web3 Festival 上，这个概念我们非常熟悉，
or we think we've been very familiar,
或者我们认为我们已经非常熟悉，
is decentralized applications.
是去中心化的应用程序。
Sometimes they call it smart contract applications.
有时他们称之为智能合约应用程序。
And essentially, it's where chain,
本质上，这就是链条，
the execution environment, the app logic,
执行环境、应用程序逻辑、
secured by the chain's economic security,
由链的经济安全保障，
what together they can do for us.
他们一起可以为我们做些什么。
Decentralization is not the goal, but better application
去中心化不是目的，而是更好的应用
than enable human agency is.
比启用人类代理是。
So there are many facets to a decentralized application.
因此，去中心化应用程序有很多方面。
And here, I've laid out essentially the on-chain
在这里，我基本上已经列出了链上
and off-chain component.
和链下组件。
What eventually goes on-chain, what gets written into the block
最终上链的内容、写入区块的内容
is the final state that's enshrined and notarized
是被铭记和公证的最终状态
into the distributed ledger, a set of valid state transitions
进入分布式账本，一组有效的状态转换
that follows a set of rules.
遵循一组规则。
And without going into too much of the jargon here,
这里不涉及太多行话，
I think that one thing I want to highlight, once again,
我想我想再次强调一件事，
we call it decentralized applications,
我们称之为去中心化应用程序，
but it's somewhat misleading.
但这有点误导。
Because decentralization, in my view, is a design commitment
因为在我看来，去中心化是一种设计承诺
and is how to make things work under the hood
以及如何让事情在幕后运作
to preserve certain guarantees that we want.
保留我们想要的某些保证。
And it should not interfere with,
而且它不应该干扰，
nor should it hinder the application experience
也不应该妨碍应用体验
that, at the end of the day, how do our intents get executed?
归根结底，我们的意图如何得到执行？
And there are a lot of details that we can dive into,
还有很多细节我们可以深入研究，
but I'll probably gloss over that when we think
但当我们思考时我可能会掩盖这一点
about decentralization, we should,
关于权力下放，我们应该，
in terms of the design process, we should separately
在设计过程中，我们应该分别
think about the chain, what the chain provides as a guarantee,
想想链条，链条提供了什么作为保证，
what the off-chain substrate enables,
链下基质可以实现什么，
and what does your smart contract application that,
你的智能合约应用程序是什么，
in my view, smart contracts are just dumb contracts.
在我看来，智能合约只是愚蠢的合约。
They don't move by themselves, but they're rule-based,
它们本身不会移动，但它们是基于规则的，
and you can reason about it, and you can verify it.
你可以推理它，你可以验证它。
And so in the past, we have been thinking about application
所以过去我们一直在思考应用
in a way that separates the app and the protocol,
以将应用程序和协议分开的方式，
but the lines are blurring.
但界限正在变得模糊。
Perhaps before I dive further into these kind of design
也许在我进一步深入研究此类设计之前
thinking and how things work under the hood,
思考以及事物在幕后如何运作，
before I lost you, I think one of the things
在失去你之前，我想一件事
that you may have in mind, and this may be the burning
你可能想到的，这可能就是燃烧
question that you've had all day long,
困扰你一整天的问题
is how does blockchain help us in applications,
是区块链如何在应用中帮助我们，
or what is even blockchain's role?
或者区块链的作用是什么？
I think a lot of the speakers before me
我想我之前的很多发言者
have explained in their own words
用自己的话解释了
and what they're working on, and we have inherited or assumed,
以及他们正在做的事情，以及我们继承或假设的，
this is the truth, but in my view,
这是事实，但在我看来，
I view this question as quite important,
我认为这个问题非常重要，
and my mental model has been blockchain
我的思维模型是区块链
help us define our shared digital reality.
帮助我们定义我们共享的数字现实。
Today we live in a world where it's
今天我们生活在一个这样的世界
full of misinformation, malinformation.
充满错误信息、错误信息。
Every single app, every single algorithm
每个应用程序，每个算法
is manipulating how we think, what we think.
正在操纵我们的思维方式和想法。
And our interaction, my interaction with TikTok
还有我们的互动，我与 TikTok 的互动
is different than my interaction with Doubao or chat GPT.
和我和豆宝或者聊天GPT的互动不一样。
And in fact, if you ask each of the algorithms what
事实上，如果你问每个算法什么
they think of me, they will tell you
他们想我，他们会告诉你
completely different versions that I wouldn't even
完全不同的版本，我什至不会
want to admit.
想要承认。
But precisely in this world, I think
但我想正是在这个世界上
that there is something that needs to lay the ground truth
有一些事情需要奠定基础事实
as what is our shared reality?
我们共同的现实是什么？
And so when we think about applications,
所以当我们考虑应用时
when we think about the human relationship with machines
当我们思考人与机器的关系时
that help us achieve what we want to achieve,
帮助我们实现我们想要实现的目标，
maybe the first question is, what is missing?
也许第一个问题是，缺少什么？
How do you know if something is real?
你怎么知道某件事是否真实？
So this is more so on a philosophical level,
所以这在哲学层面上更是如此
and I won't go into the details because I can't even
我不会详细说明，因为我什至无法
read the fine prints on my own slides.
阅读我自己的幻灯片上的精美印刷品。
It's too far away.
太远了。
And one more thing that I want to help
还有一件事我想帮忙
set the stage in terms of a shared mental model
为共同的心理模型奠定基础
is that when we think about a blockchain,
当我们想到区块链时
blockchains have blocks, right?
区块链有区块，对吗？
And the block production process nowadays
以及现在的区块生产流程
we call block building is simply a contest
我们称搭积木只是一场竞赛
under deadline with rewards.
在截止日期内有奖励。
This has been true since the Bitcoin days,
自比特币时代以来都是如此，
and this continues to be true in Ethereum
这在以太坊中仍然如此
and the future of blockchain substrate.
以及区块链底层的未来。
And within the deadline, it's all
在最后期限内，一切都完成了
about how can we pack the optimal block,
关于我们如何打包最佳块，
or how do we produce the most valuable block?
或者我们如何生产最有价值的区块？
And it is this process that actually
而实际上正是这个过程
goes into essentially the most important execution substrate
本质上进入最重要的执行基础
for blockchains.
对于区块链。
And how does this relate to what you're familiar with?
这与您所熟悉的内容有何关系？
Essentially, it's an ordering process,
本质上，这是一个订购过程，
finding what is valuable at the end of the day for you
在一天结束时找到对您有价值的东西
based on order leverage the market.
基于市场订单杠杆。
So OK, so I'm going to try to speed run through the smart
好吧，所以我要尝试加快智能运行速度
contract application patterns, or else I
合同应用模式，否则我
think your next panel will never start.
认为你的下一个小组永远不会开始。
This may bore some of you, so I'll be quick.
这可能会让你们中的一些人感到厌烦，所以我会尽快。
So essentially, here are a few, I
所以本质上，这里有一些，我
would say, characteristics of a smart contract application.
可以说，智能合约应用程序的特征。
Essentially, I really can't really see what's on my slides.
本质上，我真的看不清幻灯片上的内容。
Yeah, so basically, there is the deterministic aspect
是的，基本上，有确定性方面
that guarantees the same input, and you get the same output.
这保证了相同的输入，并且您得到相同的输出。
There is the aspect of public state that's visible to all.
公共国家的一个方面是所有人都可见的。
There's the importance of composability
可组合性的重要性
that makes essentially today what you see as Ethereum
这基本上就是今天你所看到的以太坊
very competitive when it comes to DeFi applications,
在 DeFi 应用方面非常有竞争力，
because composability is super important for liquidity.
因为可组合性对于流动性非常重要。
And finally, the permissionless nature of it,
最后，它的未经许可的性质，
that anyone can participate in the market,
任何人都可以参与市场，
anyone can deploy contracts.
任何人都可以部署合约。
And there are different roles, of course, in the system.
当然，系统中有不同的角色。
When you think about a smart contract application,
当您考虑智能合约应用程序时，
I view it as a design that is intentionally incomplete,
我认为这是一个故意不完整的设计，
as in smart contracts are dumb contracts,
就像智能合约是哑合约一样，
as I mentioned earlier.
正如我之前提到的。
And they rely on external third party, such as bots,
他们依赖外部第三方，例如机器人，
and mostly bots, to update the state.
主要是机器人来更新状态。
And so DeFi design, ever since inception,
所以 DeFi 的设计，从一开始，
has always been, in my view, designing
在我看来，设计一直是
how to leave money on the table for bots to help arbitrage
如何为机器人留下资金以帮助套利
and move the markets.
并推动市场。
And so in AMMs, as we know, arbitrage bots
正如我们所知，在 AMM 中，套利机器人
help align the price.
帮助调整价格。
Liquidations is super important for lending protocol,
清算对于借贷协议来说非常重要，
and that's basically who's doing the most valuable work
这基本上就是谁在做最有价值的工作
in those most fundamental smart contract applications
在那些最基本的智能合约应用中
that we're familiar with, is actually the bots.
我们所熟悉的，实际上是机器人。
And with intent-based architecture, aside from AMMs,
通过基于意图的架构，除了 AMM 之外，
the state of the art has become a hybrid of essentially AMMs
最先进的技术已经成为 AMM 的混合体
and off-chain solvers, as well as nowadays,
和链下求解器，以及现在，
you may have heard the fancy term this year, is prop AMM.
今年你可能听说过一个时髦的术语，那就是道具 AMM。
But essentially, how do all of these work?
但本质上，所有这些是如何运作的？
What are the invisible humming bees
看不见的嗡嗡声是什么
that's making the market for you?
这为你创造了市场吗？
Those are bots.
这些是机器人。
So in other words, application is contract,
换句话说，应用程序就是合同，
the smart or dumb contract, plus the market that completes it.
智能合约或哑合约，加上完成它的市场。
And so there's also another concept
所以还有另一个概念
that I won't dwell too much into it.
我不会过多地讨论它。
There's atomic execution, the atomicity,
有原子执行，原子性，
the importance of atomicity, and the importance
原子性的重要性，以及
of composability.
可组合性。
Those are technical jargons that just keep in mind
这些是技术术语，请记住
they will be important and relevant when
当它们变得重要且相关时
we speak about today and future agentic application.
我们谈论今天和未来的代理应用。
So to sum it up, basically, when it comes to smart contract
综上所述，基本上，当谈到智能合约时
applications, it's an open ecosystem.
应用程序，这是一个开放的生态系统。
And this design pattern helps preserve agency
这种设计模式有助于保持代理性
because it gives us the ability to understand,
因为它赋予我们理解的能力，
to act under known rules towards outcome that we can verify.
根据已知规则采取行动，以实现我们可以验证的结果。
So in fact, there is much more to the on-chain contracts
所以事实上，链上合约还有更多内容
and the off-chain bots aspect when
以及链下机器人方面
it comes to the design pattern of designing applications
涉及到设计应用程序的设计模式
that serve as human agency.
作为人类机构。
So on Ethereum, we already have atomic composition
所以在以太坊上，我们已经有了原子组成
that's basically inside one transaction, the atomicity
这基本上是在一个事务内部，原子性
aspect.
方面。
But now, how do we extend it across
但现在，我们如何将其扩展到
in the entire execution pipeline to ensure
在整个执行管道中以确保
that the guarantees that we need to execute our intent
我们需要执行我们的意图的保证
faithfully, that give us the best execution, is there?
忠实地，这给了我们最好的执行力，是吗？
So again, it goes into this part that you don't usually
再说一遍，这部分是你通常不会涉及的
hear explained when we speak about or think
当我们谈论或思考时听到解释
about applications.
关于应用程序。
Again, I go back to blocks.
我再次回到街区。
So essentially, blockchains have blocks.
所以本质上，区块链有区块。
And it's this contest under deadline, as I mentioned.
正如我提到的，这是一场在截止日期前举行的比赛。
And in fact, in the production to produce
而事实上，在生产中生产
through a competition, the most valuable block
通过竞争，选出最有价值的区块
under this deadline, thousands of counterfactual futures,
在此期限内，数以千计的反事实期货，
thousands of blocks are submitted,
提交了数千个区块，
in fact, by each of the block builder that
事实上，每个区块构建者都认为
enters in this competition.
参加本次比赛。
Just within that 12 seconds of Ethereum slot time.
就在以太坊时段的 12 秒内。
One way I like to think about it is,
我喜欢思考这个问题的一种方式是，
if you remember the Marvel comics,
如果你还记得漫威漫画
I think one of the Avengers series,
我认为复仇者联盟系列之一
there is a scene where Doctor Strange looks
有一个场景是奇异博士看起来的
into the millions of future worlds
进入数以百万计的未来世界
and finally found one where Xenos was not going to win.
终于找到了异形无法获胜的地方。
And so you can think about the block building process
所以你可以考虑块构建过程
as in real time, taking into account the entire world's
实时计算，考虑到整个世界的
information.
信息。
And then as every milliseconds go by,
然后随着每一毫秒的过去，
and then compute and recompute what is the optimal outcome.
然后计算并重新计算最佳结果是什么。
And then submit it as the deadline approaches
然后在截止日期临近时提交
into this block construction process, this market,
进入这个街区建设过程，这个市场，
this contest.
这次比赛。
And so in fact, why I focus on this analogy
事实上，为什么我关注这个类比
and this point of many possible futures
以及许多可能的未来的这一点
with one canonical block is because if you want
具有一个规范块是因为如果你想要
the state of the world, if you want something to happen.
世界的状况，如果你想要发生一些事情。